Today on the podcast, I sat down with Nathan McCauley, the co-founder and CEO of Anchorage.
As many who listen to this podcast will know, Anchorage operates a federally chartered bank
and they are a major player in the digital asset custody and stablecoin ecosystem,
along with many other product lines. This was a timely episode where we talked about
the debanking of crypto companies, talked about upcoming policy milestones and priorities,
including crypto executive orders, Saab 121 repeal, stablecoin legislation, market structure bill,
and a lot more. We also talked about the work that Anchorage is doing with institutions and protocols,
the global dollar network, as well as new product launches on the horizon.
I think you'll enjoy this one. So without further ado, here's my conversation with Nathan McCauley.
Brought down by bad mortgage investments, Lehman, which has 25,000 employees, will be liquidated.
The federal government loans American International Group, AIG, 85 billion dollars.
This is a different kind of market and the Fed is asleep.
The federal government is stepping in to stabilize Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac,
the two mortgage giants that have been threatened by the housing crisis.
The Bank of England has pumped 75 billion pounds more into Britain's ailing economy
The new round of clubs is easy.
You print a couple trillion dollars and all of a sudden people start to worry.
So out of this worry, we have something called the Bitcoin. Bitcoin.
All right, Nathan, thanks so much for joining us today on the podcast.
I can't believe you haven't been on this podcast before. So appreciate you coming on.
I've been a long time fan, Matt. So very glad to be here. Thanks for having me.
And what a week to have you on. So you testified in front of the Senate Banking Committee.
That's got to be a stressful week for you.
So one of those things where it's obviously a very high stakes situation,
certainly never would have imagined doing something like that when I was taking the
public speaking classes back in college, but nevertheless was asked to come and tell our
story there. So had a fun time there testifying and Senate Banking Committee this week.
Definitely want to get into all of that. People that listen to this podcast probably know a
good deal about Anchorage. But for those maybe who are less familiar, can you maybe just set the
table with the company, a little bit of the origin story and the lines of business that
you guys are in today? Sure. Thanks.
So Anchorage is here to serve institutions who want to participate in broadly digital
asset ecosystem. And so about seven years ago, me and my co-founder Diogo started the company
on the assumption that institutions would want to come into digital assets. And at the time,
late 2017, early 2018, there were a ton of people in retail that were participating in digital assets,
but basically no institutional offerings. There wasn't institutional custodians. There was very
few that I think the most institutional trading venue you had was Coinbase Pro. And so it was just
a white space. And the basic bet was, hey, if this is going to be an asset class, it's not going to
be entirely driven by retail. It'll also be driven by institutions. And so let's build a set of tools
for institutional investors. The natural starting point on that journey was digital asset custody,
particularly some of the large investors have to satisfy what's called the qualified custody rule.
So they need to hold assets with a qualified custodian. And so we started out with a custody
system that really is still kind of the central point of our company. That's our largest business
line. And the biggest set of value that we bring to the clients is a safe and secure custody
solution. We wanted to take a little bit of a contrarian take with the way that we built custody.
We were not interested in the cold storage solutions where you have to take the assets,
take them offline, and then never get to touch them. We assumed that the digital asset ecosystem
would mean that you actually want to do stuff with the digital assets. What we now understand
to be things like staking, things like participating in DeFi governance. So the basic tenant at the
beginning was people want to do stuff with their assets, they want to hold it in a super safe way,
and they want the whole thing to be regulated. And so along that journey, we pursued regulatory
licensure from the very beginning of the company. And then that eventually culminated in us getting
the federal bank charter we have with the OCC. So this has been a large part of our differentiation
is the fact that we have this national bank charter. We can hold a whole host of digital
asset for institutional investors. And maybe just wrapping up on this, right now, what this means
is that we serve basically all of the large holders and types of holders of digital assets,
whether it's the VC funds that hold their tokens, their holding that they've invested in,
the digital asset protocols themselves. A lot of protocols decide that they'll TGE with us
and hold their initial supply with Anchorage and then use us as the distribution mechanism out for
that. And then ETF issuers hold their assets at Anchorage as a safe, qualified custodial bank for
those assets, all the way up to some of the world's sovereign wealth funds choose to hold
their assets with us. So it's kind of that whole landscape of digital asset investors
hold their assets with us. Along that trajectory, it made sense to add additional services. And so
we provide staking services for them. We provide trading services and tri-party and settlement
services, really all of the stuff that an institution needs in order to support their
investment thesis and grow their business. And that's really where we focus.
Trey Lockerbie I can definitely attest as a user,
a customer, that it's an exceptional platform. The tech is incredible. I think one of the more
interesting things that you did highlight there is just the way that you guys went about becoming
a qualified custodian, going this OCC path. It's pretty remarkable, giving everything that's
happened over the past three, four years, that was a pathway that you were able to achieve.
Maybe talk a little bit about what that process was like and maybe what it's been like after you
got the Charter. David Morgan
It's a great question. It's been a really funny and fun story for us. That's played out a lot
of different ways, some of them quite surprising. But generally speaking, we wanted to solve this
qualified custody rule for our clients. That meant that we ourselves needed to get regulated. At the
time, this was an impossible problem. No one knew how digital asset firms should be regulated,
how they should be set up. And so the initial starting hypothesis was actually to try to get
a broker dealer. Broker dealers are allowed to be qualified custodians. Spent a bunch of time on
that and ended up being a little bit of a dead end. And then we pivoted from that strategy to
get a state charter trust company. State charter trust company that we got out of South Dakota
allowed us to start operating. We were able to act as a qualified custodian. A lot of our initial
growth happened once we got that Charter in South Dakota. Opportunity presented itself in the kind
of last year of the Trump administration, where there was an opportunity to convert our state
charter into a national trust bank. And so we went through a conversion process where we turned
that state chartered institution into a federally chartered institution. It took a lot of work,
obviously. That's a very serious thing to create a national bank. Lots of compliance processes
needed. Really, when you create a national bank, the way the government views it is that you're
creating literally a permanent entity. Like it is expected that the thing that gets created
is a permanent fixture. Early on in the process, they wanted to talk about things like continuity
plans, like what happens when I retire. And at some point I was like, guys, I'm 30, 35.
That's not something we need to worry about yet, but that's the kind of timeframes we're
thinking about when you create a national bank. And so we completed that conversion process.
And so in early January of 2021, we started operating as a national bank. This was huge
for us because there's a lot of industry participants that took that signal, like, hey,
we got a national bank crypto now. That's almost a tacit approval that is possible to do this
business. It's possible to participate in the digital asset ecosystem. A lot of clients and
client growth came as a result of getting that charter. Interestingly, in our charter,
we actually got four activities that were allowed to do with our charter, custody of digital assets,
staking of digital assets, settlement of digital assets, and governance of digital assets.
And so this is pretty cool because of that staking and governance ones. To my knowledge,
we're actually the first incarnations of the federal government saying that those activities
were even legal and weren't even allowed at all. The participating in staking, participating in
governance. And so we're really proud of that. And to use that to really grow the business,
onboard a lot of clients, and really provide a lot of value to the ecosystem.
It's been crazy to see that pathway just got shut down after you guys got it,
at least from my perspective. And so what was your view on just the ability to retain that license
even? It had to have been pretty hairy over the past couple of years, just given all of the
operation choke point type of activities that were going on in the industry.
Yeah, it ends up being an interesting thing. So when banks get chartered, as mentioned, I think
my team did some research on this. The OCC was actually established by Abraham Lincoln.
And as far as we understand it, there has not been an OCC charter that's been revoked since Abraham
Lincoln established the OCC. And so there's like this long history that speaks to exactly what I
talked about earlier, which is the charters are permanent. They are a permanent institution.
Now, that's not to say that things can't be made quite difficult and existing and working
under that regulatory scrutiny. But in a lot of ways, I think the regulatory scrutiny that we were
under is why a lot of clients trusted us, particularly, I would say, a lot of other
national banks. There were a lot of other national banks and state banks that were
actively looking at partnerships with us because of the fact that we had that charter.
And they said to themselves, okay, we don't want to become a Codivist Custodian ourselves,
but we'd like to participate in the digital asset ecosystem. Why don't we build out a business
model, whether it's using Anchorage as a sub-custodian, referring clients over and
then lending against those assets, or thinking about things with tokenization where Anchorage
could be a partner to us. And so they handle the regulatory licensure of the custody of the digital
assets, but we can build a crypto business, use them as infrastructure. This is actually
common with custody banks, BNY, State Street, Northern Trust. Many of them act as the custodian
for the other banks. And so this was a very nicely growing opportunity for us there
directly after our chartering process. That makes sense. So I want to talk a little bit about the
debanking over the past few years. So we became aware of this, I would say, just from our vantage
point of trying to fund early stage businesses and some of them having a really hard time getting
bank accounts and other companies, our portfolio, just getting cashier's checks from their banks
and saying, look, you're shut down, take the money elsewhere and really panicking and having
to scramble to make payroll, try to get onboarded somewhere else. When did you become aware that
there was some sort of a coordinated activity against the crypto industry? And curious what
your journey was in terms of getting vocal about it, because I think you've done a great service
for the industry and just talking to some of the politicians and making it broadly aware that,
look, something bad is happening here. Yeah, I think that the first indication
on our side actually of that was not what you guys have correctly identified as debanking kind
of industry-wide. Our first indication of it was those very partnerships that I was just talking
about, the large national banks and regional banks that wanted to get into digital assets,
literally were looking at building digital asset businesses, paused those partnership
conversations. So this is like the first hint that something is wrong because we've got like
an industry-wide trend that all of a sudden vanishes. All of a sudden, nobody is interested
in becoming a subsodian. Nobody is interested in lending against digital assets. Nobody is
interested in doing these kinds of things. But I think that's actually really important to note
here that all of them were actively trying to become crypto banks themselves. That's the
starting point mental model I have in your head. Banks wanted to come into crypto and were actively
working on it. And so those things start to dry up. And then we see a steady stream of regulatory
filings, maybe some people would call them rules, interpretations, really across a broad swath of the
industry. A lot of the attention in the industry focused on this particularly, I don't know,
hilarious one called SAB 121, which was a deeply specific accounting interpretation that made it
impossible for any national bank to come into digital assets because of the way they would
have to reserve against those assets. So that one got a lot of press almost spent a bunch of time
on that. Related to that, those of us that are in the banking industry and follow the kind of banking
nerds, if you will, saw a bunch of these coming out. FDIC had their own interpretive letter that
came out. The OCC had an interpretive letter called OCC Interpretive Letter 1179 that specified
it was actually interpretation that they had that said, you have to come and ask us if you want to
do with anything in digital assets. Typically, banks are allowed to do whatever they want.
They have to follow what are called safety and soundness guidelines, but they have broad flexibility
to almost self-regulate. The way the banks are set up is they have a whole set of internal processes
that functionally act as a self-regulatory system. And then the regulators come in and look at those
and make sure that the machine that is the self-regulatory apparatus inside the bank is
continuing to run as stated. If you get to the point where your regulators trust you that much,
that's what you're able to do. And so this letter that comes out of the OCC says,
no, you can't decide for yourself on this anymore. You got to come ask us if you can do anything on
that. And our understanding is all of those conversations terminated in don't do it. Like
they said, you got to come ask and then don't do it. That's what happened there. Adding onto that,
there's this joint letter that came out from Fed, FDIC, and OCC that starts out in its preamble.
Banks can do whatever they want. And then follows up with, here's a laundry list, a litany
of risky things. And then concludes with, we think doing this stuff is highly unlikely to be
consistent with safe and sound banking practices, which to most people is, okay, that's like a
pretty boring drab statement, but it's actually like an outright ban. When you see highly unlikely
to be inconsistent with safe and sound banking practices, every bank CEO in the country reads
that. Okay, I see what they're trying to say. Do not do that. And so then after that one,
that's where we actually saw what you guys have described as debanking. This is where people
started losing their accounts. This is where people started getting kicked off the platforms.
I heard about this in some cases from my, I have a bit of an angel investment. I like to invest in
my friends, invest in other people around, and started to hear stories of people losing their
bank accounts. And then the culmination of that was it actually happened to us. And so that was
a nice part of the Senate testimony is like talking a little bit about the story that actually
happened to us as a national bank getting debanked.
Adam Felsenfeld So I guess after all of this, and you're
down there this week, you're testifying from the Senate banking, are you optimistic that
this is changing the new roster, the cast of characters down there or understanding what
happened and taking corrective action?
Adam Felsenfeld Yeah, I am. I think that if you look at
the point of this hearing that we had this week, it was really just about getting the ideas out
there. The Senate in particular wanted to cast a broad brush on what's happening here. And so I
was the one crypto witness where I talked about how this has happened within the crypto industry.
But then they, within the Senate, wanted to talk about general problem, particularly because I
think President Trump is interested in this idea of potentially conservatives getting debanked,
other disfavored industries also getting debanked. And so it's like a broad question of how do we,
just at this point, understand, shine a light on what happened here? And so that was really
the point of this hearing. That's the one where I shared the Anchorage story of getting debanked,
which I don't want to spend a bunch of time on it. But broadly speaking, we had a bank that we had
a growing relationship with. We'd had them for several years, actively discussing new partnerships.
And then just one day, they call us and say, hey, it's over, your account is closed.
And this is particularly ironic because we are a national bank ourselves. There couldn't be a more
regulated, safe partner to work with within the digital asset industry. It's like a banking
account, a basic checking account for a bank. And so us getting our account closed was used as
illustrative purpose in the banking hearing, Senate banking hearing, just to talk about like
where this kind of happened, how pervasive it was. And so step one is shine a light on this.
There's some discussion about what could happen moving forward. I think there's kind of two camps
emerging on which way things should go. And so at least in some sense, there's some room for optimism
here in that maybe the Republican side is looking at, okay, how do we make sure that
this doesn't happen anymore on behalf of regulatory overreach, if you will. And then I would say,
nicely, even someone like Senator Warren is looking at this and saying, how do we make sure
that this doesn't happen to disfavored political groups, whether it's some of the groups that she
mentioned, minority groups that may have had a debanking happen, all the way to the idea of
conservatives being debanked. General agreement across both sides of the aisle that this isn't
the way that policy should get carried out. It shouldn't be that people lose their bank accounts
due to political disfavor, due to discrimination, if you will. Overall, it felt like pretty positive.
And I'm going to be carefully tracking where we go from here.
Soterios Johnson I'm really excited to see where we go and
want to dive a little bit into some of the policy milestones here that are about to happen,
and in some cases just did happen. And maybe we could look at them a little bit just through
the lens of how positive they are for Anchorage, because I think there's a lot of positive momentum
here. You mentioned Saab 121, and I think this is just fascinating if you look at it through the
lens of, okay, the banks can now play in the custody space. Very few of them have really embarked
down the mission of building their own custody stack. And so if you're on the inside of one of
these bigger banks that plays in the non-crypto custody space, you're probably having a build
versus buy versus partner conversation here. And I would have to think a lot of those institutions
would be looking at sub-custody as just the fastest way to get something out. Is that the
right way to think about what's about to happen here in the broader banking space?
Soterios Johnson Yeah, I think that's exactly what's going to happen. The reason we've been
consistently against Saab 121, despite the fact that it basically cut out the whole industry from
competing with us. So one interpretation of it is it gave us a monopoly on crypto banking,
which is cool. But on the other hand, it's kind of un-American as well. And so our basic
thing to regulators there was maybe this isn't the best. And a lot of the reason for that is
exactly what you said. Most of the banks are going to want to choose a sub-custodian partner
that they'll want to work with, and they're going to choose to work with a national bank.
We had already kicked off once those conversations before some of this got shut down. Those are
picking up and already picking up in earnest in a real way. So I expect one of the themes of our
public messaging for the rest of the year is going to be announcing some of these partnerships,
where Wall Street firms are going to decide, hey, it's time to partner with a digital asset
firm in order to get something to market. And then that's the way to get to market fast,
deliver value to your clients, and get this really going. The alternative path is to decide
to become a custodian themselves and build it internally. You're at Fidelity for a long time.
What they have pulled off is a modern business miracle. It is incredible that they have built
a custody system internally that holds Bitcoin. People should write books about how incredible
that effort has succeeded. But I think a lot of people look at that and the great success there
has thus far only gotten them to Bitcoin. And that's just not the shape of the ecosystem.
There are so many different assets. And so people look at even just like the asset support
complexity over time and say, hey, if we want to really participate in this space,
it's going to have to be a partner program where we partner with somebody. And I think a lot of
them are going to decide, hey, this is not just tech that we need. It's also regulatory solve.
And working like an Anchorage gets us both at the same time.
I would love to be on the inside of some of these board discussions at these banks specifically,
because you look at this and say, okay, we could build it, but is that three years? Is that four
years? How many people are we going to have to hire? Can we actually hire the right people?
Or then you look at M&A and there just actually aren't that many things to buy. It seems like a
very interesting market structure, but there's just not a lot of options. And I would think that
the sub-custody just becomes the fastest way to get something out.
Will Barron I think that's right.
The amount of recruiting that needs to happen in order to build a team that can build this whole
thing. And then you have to retain them through down cycles. You have to keep your composure.
As crypto goes into a bear market, continue working on it through the bear market. If you're
trying to get something done on a reasonable time horizon, partnership ends up being the way to
actually have success. And you're right. Putting it bluntly, there's many banks that would like
to come in and relatively few custodians. Like I mentioned before, this isn't a surprising
situation. This is how most of the large banks choose to implement custody anyways,
is they'll partner with a BMI or State Street to be their custodian bank. They'll stay into the
other businesses that are more in their lane. And so assuming that that will happen within
the digital asset ecosystem is actually, you might even say the base case assumption of how this
market structure plays out. Yeah, that's spot on. So I want to talk next about stablecoins.
It seems like the stablecoin bill is the one that could potentially get brought up before
market structure. Although I'd love your thoughts on that, but it seems like stablecoins are
pretty far down the path of having some sort of a bipartisan consensus. There's bills that
have been drafted in the House and the Senate. I want to get your view on just where that
legislation is. And then we'd love to use that as an opportunity to talk about global dollar
network and how you guys have thought about playing the stablecoin space.
This is a funny one, Matt. I think the new administration coming in is just moving
incredibly quickly and this speed of execution almost feels contagious. And so in a lot of the
conversations I had in the Senate, even over the last couple of weeks, has been like, hey,
we want to move. We want to move quick. We want to follow in that wake. We had the incredible
press conference from David Sacks, where David got up with congressional leadership and Senate
leadership to chart the course for regulatory clarity coming to the digital asset industry
and specifically talk about stablecoin bills, which then got introduced in the same day,
and then the even broader one of Brown market structure. So current best guess,
which by the way, it changes all the time, but current best guess looks like we're looking at
stablecoin legislation likely coming first, then followed by market structure. Right now we've got
two versions of these bills. We've got the Hagerty bill in the Senate, and then the House
complement to that, that each of them have a bunch of good ideas. And I think there's going
to be room for some thoughtful debate about the way we want to go here. But I think the larger
point comes to this point that David Sacks made, which is this must be a strategic asset of the
United States. So Trump talked about that back at Bitcoin Nashville. David Sacks is singing from
the same hymnal now and talking about this needs to happen. And so I think that's a big reason why
stablecoins might be coming first is that they understand that this is key to dollar dominance
over the next century.
Soterios Johnson I think that's spot on. And so I guess the logical next question to that is,
who's going to want to enter this market? Do you issue your own stablecoin? Do you join a syndicate?
You guys must have thought about launching your own stablecoin at some point, I'd imagine. But
what led you to this global dollar network concept?
David Sacks The global dollar network is, at its core,
the idea there is a couple of things come to mind. First of all, we need a regulated, globally
accepted dollar. And if you just think about the way that the dollar itself works,
the way that the dollar itself works is that it's fair in that the people that interact with
the dollar are able to build business models on the dollar where they share in the economics.
And so as an example, banks hold dollars, and then they have a direct business model they can
build on top of that. Payments companies build on top of the dollar, and they have a natural
business model they can build on that. Unfortunately, if you look at something like USDC,
it does not have a model where you can actually build on it together.
What happens with USDC is all of the yield, all of the financial participation goes to two entities,
that one of those entities happens to be competitive with the entire crypto market.
And so that's like a little bit of a bummer there. All things considered, it would have been nice to
not have to do something new. And if we had just had an existing stablecoin that actually could be
global infrastructure, it would have been nicer to stick with that. Unfortunately,
one doesn't exist and certainly isn't USDC. So what we need is something that actually
shares in the economic opportunity with everybody that's contributing to it.
And so what happened with the global dollar was basically that notion that I just shared with you,
a series of probably five, six crypto CEOs came to me and said, hey, Nathan, can you please
make a stablecoin that's fair and that we can all work together on?
Because somebody was like, hey, I've minted billions in USDC, holding hundreds of millions,
and I'm getting nothing. And I was like, oh, yeah, that's true. And then you hear this enough and
you're like, okay, something else needs to happen. So that nucleus is the core of the idea of a global
dollar where we can bring everybody in to this stablecoin and then they can share in the economics.
The other theory on is like, why does it need to be a consortium? Why not just have each and every
one of us make our own dollar, Anchorage dollar, Kraken dollar, Robinhood dollar, whatever.
And then that's where you come to, okay, we need global liquidity to be able to work together.
And so the consortium model, I think, is the winning model where a bunch of people come
together and say, hey, we're going to work together on a stablecoin. It's going to
share economics with the distributors, those who are helping to grow the network.
Those distributors can decide to, however it works for them,
share in some of that with their clients. But generally speaking, it should be a scalable
stablecoin. And early indications just from the kind of the reach out that we're getting there
is that this is a really powerful idea. A lot of people are coming to us and say, hey,
I want to join the consortium. I want to be part of this. I want to take global dollar and have a
pronounced experience within my interface. And so I think what you're going to see over the next
several months is a lot more people join that consortium and say, I want to be part of this.
I want to be part of this global dollar that I can actually be regulated, fair,
and actually act as market infrastructure for the whole ecosystem.
I've often thought about what this would look like at true institutional scale.
If you wanted to use a stablecoin to settle overnight repos, I don't think there's anything
in the market right now that's just big enough to facilitate that. And you'd have credit risk
issues. But it does seem like the consortium model is maybe the only one that could really
get you to that level where you're doing true TradFi settlements and taking advantage of a
blockchain to cut out access to the Fed wire window at the end of the day.
Yeah, I think that's right.
So it'll be interesting to see how that plays out. The other catalyst here, I think for you guys,
would be a market structure bill. And we've gone through this whole history of crypto without
having clarity on tokenized securities. And there's all sorts of ideas that have been
bandied about around taking things that exist in the real world, actually having the token itself
be a security. Will Anchorage be a player in that market as it develops here?
The tokenized securities area is, it's interesting. We've, as I mentioned earlier,
been looking at broker-dealer from the very inception of the company, always assumed things
would go in this direction, that assets would be brought on chain. Stablecoins are the first
instantiation of this, but why not bring in other things? As far as I understand right now, we are
the largest custodian in the world of tokenized T-bills, tokenized money market funds, big in
Biddle, big in SuperState, and then some of the others. We're going to be a big player in this
space. I think exactly what the economic models are for this, what drives adoption into these assets
is something that is still to be figured out. There's still some good experimentation to be
done. A lot of that experimentation though was hard without a market structure bill.
You're correct to point out that market structure and clarity around this is going to drive
some of what I would call the product discovery that needs to happen there, and that product
discovery will lead to the use cases that really take hold. Unfortunately, this is one where
the regulatory uncertainty is maybe in meaningful ways holding back the experimentation that is
actually wanted to figure out exactly how this plays out. Market structure being something that's
on the docket for this year is pretty exciting, and that we could really get that unlocked that
allows the experimentation that's needed. I've probably sound like a broken record
on market structure on this podcast because I talk about the need for a bill to get this clarity,
and then you figure out how the secondary trading can work. Sometimes I forget that the SEC can
actually do rulemaking and propose rules and work with industry, and it actually seems like that is
starting immediately even though we don't have a confirmed commissioner of the SEC. So maybe you
end up in a world where the SEC has put out some proposed rules and that coalesces well into a
market structure bill. I think that's actually a really important point to make, and this is not
specific to the SEC. The SEC can release interpretive guidance that provides a clear
road. The banking regulators can provide interpretive guidance and provide a clear road,
and so can the CFTC. And so, actually, the federal regulatory agency has a broad set of latitude
to themselves decide that this will happen. Where we might need to think about the market
structure bill is how each of those agencies interact. Some of the cross-agency dependencies
are probably most appropriate for a bill to come through, but you're right. A broad set of latitude
and understanding can come through the regulatory agencies themselves, drawing the path forward.
Soterios Johnson That market structure bill,
at least in my mind, is something that has the potential to spur just a ton of innovation and
net new companies and protocols getting off the ground. Just take Filecoin, for example,
and how much money they've had to spend on legal fees over the years and have this question of,
okay, is this thing a security? Is it a commodity? But if there's actually a clear path there,
I just think you'll see more protocol innovation. I would imagine the protocol
side of your business would actually benefit tremendously.
Adam Felsen I think so. I think there's a huge amount of
entrepreneurs that want to build protocols, and I think that's part of what's been sad about some
of the amount of regulatory uncertainty has been, frankly, the number of protocols that have not
come into existence. It's very natural for us to talk about how much Filecoin has gone through
on the debate of security or not security. It's much harder to tell the story of the Filecoin
that was never to be because of people not coming into this. And I think that the underwater part of
the iceberg that is really worth considering. That's why I think you're exactly right. There's
a bunch more that'll happen once we have clarity and rules the road here.
Soterios Johnson You're an entrepreneur,
you know what it's like, but you don't want to sign up for just getting punched in the face for
four years. I think there's a lot of ideas out there that now will be attempted. So that'll be
super interesting to see. I'd love to maybe just talk a little bit about what's on deck here and
what you guys have pushed out from a product perspective as we close. Maybe talk a little
bit about Porto Wallet, and I think that's been a great product addition for Anchorage.
Chris Bounds Yeah, we got two growth areas that have
been really helpful to the overall Anchorage product suite. The first one is Porto, second one I'll
come back to is Atlas. But Porto has been wonderful in that it takes the very nice usable aspects of
the Anchorage digital system, makes it available in a self custody wallet so that people can decide
basically use it as software to allow them to do whatever they might want with that. A lot of the
people that are using Porto are using it for on chain interactions. So being able to interact
with smart contracts, we got some protocols actually that are the entire orchestration of
their protocol is now running out of Porto. And so this has been like a really good use case where
really just administrating the protocol itself is happening through Porto.
And then a whole host of say funds like yourself or trading funds that are looking to do
on chain ARBs take the Porto infrastructure and allow them to do on chain interactions.
It's really a nice wallet in that it allows you to do not just Ethereum based transactions,
but also other layer ones you can work with as well. So very flexible, but also easy to use.
And so we're pretty proud of that and looking to see that grow over the next year.
Next one I'll just mention briefly is Atlas. Atlas is a really nice
settlement tool that allows people to do both bilateral and tripartite relationships.
And so the easiest example is like who goes first in an OTC trade? Do I send the Bitcoin or do you
send the ETH or who sends the dollars? What Atlas allows you to do is both sides commit and then
the swap happens simultaneously. This dramatically reduces counterparty risk and we think is going
to be necessary as institutions come into this space. There's a lot of institutions that come
into crypto and the first head explode that they have is settlement isn't solved. Really like
somebody has to go first and this is debate that we have in the contracts. And so getting that
solved at an institutional level, I think is going to be a big unlock to really make the whole
ecosystem and institutional infrastructure safer and feel and smell more like what traditional
finance feels like. And frankly, as boring as that might sound, it's actually going to be a big
unlock for institutions to be able to come in. And it turns out that once you have that base layer
of safe settlement, there's all kinds of interesting stuff that you can build on that, say,
tripartite lending agreements where people can hold assets as collateral, somebody else can lend
against them. And Atlas, I think is going to be really big for banks that want to come in.
Particularly, they don't want to become the crypto custodian, but they have a good amount of
cash that they'd like to lend against crypto. And so you can use Atlas to allow the clients to hold
the Bitcoin or other assets as a collateral asset for a loan and have the tripartite
relationship set up really nicely so that they can perfect security interest in the collateral
and use that to build up a business model there. So Atlas and Porto, I think are really
a nice growth areas this year and going to be interesting to see how they play out.
I know it's not one-to-one comparable necessarily, but Atlas in some ways makes me think of the
Silvergate Exchange Network and just how critical the piece of infrastructure that was for a moment.
And it's crazy to think that as an industry in some categories, we just have inferior
infrastructure than we did two or three years ago. And it just seems like there's a lot to be built
there on that settlement side. It's a bit of a bummer, but I think the way that we thought
about it is, how do you go beyond something like a SEN or a Cygnet? What does that really look like?
And our theory on that is that it should be dollars in crypto should be able to settle in
that instant transparent way. And so not just the dollar leg, but that bilateral relationship,
being able to build up the tri-party relationships on that. And so we're thinking about it as a bit
of a bigger vision than something as unfortunately basic that we no longer have, which is like
instant settlement of dollars. So yeah, we want to make sure that's front and center and that's
almost a spiritual successor to something like a SEN or a Silvergate.
Nathan, appreciate you coming on the podcast and thanks for all you're doing for the industry in
terms of getting out there and actually telling the story. Being the credible person that we can
put in front of regulators and politicians, it goes a long way. Where can we send people to learn
more about Anchorage and the product lineup? A few places. Anchorage.com is our website.
And then feel free to hit me up. I'm Nathan at Anchorage.com. If you want to email me,
I can help bring people into the ecosystem and get started with accounts at Anchorage.
Awesome. I enjoyed this. Thanks for coming on.
Thanks so much for having me, Matt. Appreciate it.
Thanks for listening to another episode of On the Brink with Castle Island. To find out more about
Castle Island, visit castleisland.vc. To listen to all of our podcast episodes, please go to
onthebrink-podcast.com or just click on the tab in our website. Thanks for listening.